The Zone of Interest is a drama, history, war film directed by Jonathan Glazer.
The commandant of Auschwitz, Rudolf Höss, and his wife Hedwig, strive to build a
dream life for their family in a house and garden next to the camp.
Rudolf Höss, played by Christian Friedel.
Hedwig Höss, played by Sandra Hüller.
Claus Höss, played by Johann Karthaus.
Hans Höss, played by Luis Noah Witte.
Inge-Brigit Höss, played by Nele Ahrensmeier.
Heideraud Höss, played by Lilli Falk.
The Zone of Interest is a 2023 historical drama film
written and directed by Jonathan Glazer.
Loosely based on the 2014 novel by Martin Amis, the film focuses on the life of German Auschwitz commandant Rudolf Höss and his wife
Hedwig, who live with their family in a home in the "Zone of Interest" next to  the Auschwitz concentration camp.
Christian Friedel stars as Rudolf Höss alongside Sandra Hüller as Hedwig Höss.
Development began in 2014 around the publication of the Amis
novel, which was partially based on real events.
Glazer opted to tell the story of the real Hösses rather than the characters they inspired and conducted extensive
research into the family, as he sought to demystify the perpetrators of the Holocaust as "mythologically evil".
The project was formally announced in 2019, with A24 confirmed to distribute.
Filming took place primarily around Auschwitz in mid-2021.
Additional filming took place in Jelenia Góra in January 2022.
The Zone of Interest premiered at the 76th Cannes Film Festival on 19 May 2023 and was theatrically released
in the United States on 15 December 2023, receiving acclaim and grossing over $52 million.
It received five nominations (including Best Picture) at the 96th Academy Awards, winning Best International Feature (the first for a non-English British film) and Best Sound; won the Grand Prix at Cannes and three British Academy Film Awards, becoming the
first film to win both Best Film Not in the English Language and Outstanding British Film; received three nominations at the Golden Globe Awards; and was named one of the top five international films of 2023 by the National Board of Review.
It has been regarded as one of the greatest films
of the 2020s and the 21st century.
The film explores themes of husband wife relationship, based on novel
or book, nazi, concentration camp, holocaust (shoah).
The tone is emotional.